um what advice would you give to them about if they want to try to do something big in this world they want to really have a big positive impact what advice would you give them about their career maybe about life in general
try to be useful um you do things that are useful to your fellow human beings to the world it's very hard to be useful um very hard um you know are you contributing more than you consume you know like uh like can you try to have a positive net contribution to society
if you live a useful life that is a good life a life worth having lived um you know and I like I said I would I would encourage people to I use the mental tools of physics and apply them broadly in life
what I encourage people to read a lot of books just read like basically try to ingest as much information as you can uh and try to also just develop a good general knowledge
and then try to find something where there's an overlap of your talents and what you're interested in so people may be good at something but although they may have skill at a particular thing but they don't like doing it so you want to try to find a thing where you have your that's a good a good uh combination of of your of the things that you're inherently good at but you also like doing
are you you both good at it you like doing it and it will actually have positive impact but you got to learn about things somehow So reading a broad range it's just a really read it you know more important was that kid I I read through the encyclopedia uh so that's pretty helpful
but I you know I put a lot of stock in certainly have a lot of respect for someone who puts in an honest day's work uh to do useful things and and just generally to have like not a zero-sum mindset
if you sort of say like when when we see people like have some including some very smart people kind of taking an attitude of like like doing things that seem like morally questionable it's often because they have at a base sort of axiomatic level a zero-sum mindset
when you think about education and self-education what do you recommend so there's the university there is a self-study there is uh Hands-On sort of finding a company or a place or a set of people that do the thing you're passionate about and joining them as early as possible
and you talk to people from different walks of life and different uh Industries and professions and skills and occupations like just try you know learn as much as possible